foreign
of the pitch today we have with us the
director of Olympic and paralympic
programs and Client Services good
morning Lindsay thanks for being with us
hi good morning thanks Tammy I know most
of our audience knows you for your role
as the Director of testing but one area
that we haven't covered in the pitch is
client services so thanks so much for
joining us today to chat all things
Client Services let's go ahead and Jump
Right In can you tell us what exactly
does a client service team do at usada
and what services do you provide yeah I
would be happy to the client services
team really helps coordinate and support
gold standard in and out of competition
testing in the U.S for clients
um these clients often range from ngbs
who are requesting testing outside the
scope of usada international federations
who request testing on U.S or non-us
athletes that are living training here
in the U.S other National anti-doping
organizations who have athletes here and
as well as any other organization that
wishes to start an anti-doping program
that falls outside the Olympic
paralympic umbrella
um one of the key pieces when we talk
about the services we provide is we're
not just testing those so we work with
all of our departments here at usada so
we offer education therapeutic use
exemptions science and intelligence and
results Management Services awesome
thanks I can vouch for that as the
Director of Elite Education I'm hearing
from your team all the time about
education we can provide for these
clients so tell us what types of clients
are you looking to partner with yeah our
partners really need to share usada's
mission and vision and that's in
protecting clean Sport and a level
playful field for all athletes we work
with many different shape sizes of
organizations and this is either to
develop Implement anti-doping programs
that really need to fit their needs
their budget and just ensure that we're
truly putting the athlete first and
getting a true robust anti-doping
program in place whether they've worked
with us previously want to build a
program or just begin to have those
conversations and develop one we have
the tools we have the expertise to get
you know all of our clients exactly
where they need to be
yeah I I can think of a couple great
partners that we've worked with but do
you have an example of what a good
partnership that you've developed over
the years has been and what made it
specifically successful
yeah you know some of our most important
Partnerships are those with our
International federations those
Partnerships have led us to be able to
collaborate in launching new testing
initiatives
um collaborating on Research
opportunities and implementing strategic
testing
um having those strong and very
consistent relationships just helps us
better serve athletes and be a voice for
them while partnering to truly provide a
gold standard program yeah okay so how
can people get in touch with the client
services team yeah that that's the easy
part so you can go to our website
um we do have a section on there called
choose usada you can contact us directly
through the website or you can email us
at any time at clientservices usada.org
awesome Lindsay thank you so much for
your time today uh that wraps up this
episode of the pitch we'll see you next
time yep thank you Tammy
[Music]